<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-17T11:48:44-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Elder Parscal Requested a Transfer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/24/Elder-Parscal-English-Speaking.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elder Parscal Requested a Transfer" /><published>2000-11-24T20:57:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-24T20:57:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/24/Elder-Parscal-English-Speaking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/24/Elder-Parscal-English-Speaking.html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow, what a day today. Elder Parscal went and talked with the mission president, called his mom, and decided to get transferred to an English mission. We don’t know where he is going, but it will probably be stateside. Class was good today. In between A class and Dinner, I memorized another line on discussion #1. I wish that my family would write me some letters. I also wish Kathy would, too.</p>

<p>I know that I should be devoting all my time to the Lord, but I feel that not hearing from anyone in my what seems like a long time is starting to get to me.</p>

<p>I don’t want to call it homesickness, because I don’t think that is what it is. I guessI am just feeling a lack of love. I have already lost two companions, that is kind of rough. I like Elder Reich, my companion, but he is rather cocky and headstrong. That is difficult. I want to love him, and even though he says arrogant things a lot, I try and make him feel like I am not abandoning him. I know that I am trying really hard to like him. It is not easy, but I feel that it is very important.</p>

<p>I did a lot of studying today and it felt really good to spend my time wisely.</p>

<p>I know that the the Lord loves me and He has blessed me greatly. I love the Lord so much. He has helped me be happy during this this trying time. He has helped me to be strong and has blessed me with the ability to “bounce back.”</p>

<p>Working with and helping Elder Parscal has really drained me physically and mentally. The Lord has buoyed me up in spirit and has blessed me greatly. He has rejuvenated me and helped me so much. I just love it here at the MTC. I am so grateful for all that I have: my family, my friends, my district, my branch, my companions.</p>

<p>I love it here. The Lord is wonderful and great. I love him so much. I am late for bed.</p>

<p>Goodnight.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jethro Jones</name></author><category term="companions" /><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thanksgiving 2000</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/23/thanksgiving-2000.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thanksgiving 2000" /><published>2000-11-23T21:03:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-23T21:03:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/23/thanksgiving-2000</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/23/thanksgiving-2000.html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, Wednesday night Elder Parscal starting packing up his stuff to leave. It was as I was finishing writing last night. Elder Reich and I stayed up with him until 1 am. I talked a lot and felt the Spirit guiding me somewhat in the words I should say. We decided to fast for him today, Thanksgiving day [what was I thinking?]. We fasted as a district. We asked him to pray to know if he should stay here. He still says that he shouldn’t. So, he is meeting with President Edman, the MTC Mission President Friday morning sometime. I don’t think he will stay. President Mendenhall, our branch President told me that Elder Parscal had been a toss up since day one. He said that he wanted to transfer Elder Parscal to an English speaking mission. I hope he does that as opposed to having him go home.</p>

<p>Thanksgiving was an awesome day, even though I didn’t get to eat the Thanksgiving feast; it was still wonderful. We had programs, three of them that lasted two hours each. There was a lot of singing and talents being shown. The Spirit was strong. At the end, we watched a movie called “Christmas Mission.” It was an actual movie, and at the beginning there were previews. The previews started out okay, and the person in charge started to fast-forward it, and then there was a picture of two people getting ready to have sex. They quickly stopped the tape, and it was really funny. A guy played a song on the piano called “La Conovelse[?]. It was so fast. He was like a lightning bullet with his fingers.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="holiday" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Okay, Wednesday night Elder Parscal starting packing up his stuff to leave. It was as I was finishing writing last night. Elder Reich and I stayed up with him until 1 am. I talked a lot and felt the Spirit guiding me somewhat in the words I should say. We decided to fast for him today, Thanksgiving day [what was I thinking?]. We fasted as a district. We asked him to pray to know if he should stay here. He still says that he shouldn’t. So, he is meeting with President Edman, the MTC Mission President Friday morning sometime. I don’t think he will stay. President Mendenhall, our branch President told me that Elder Parscal had been a toss up since day one. He said that he wanted to transfer Elder Parscal to an English speaking mission. I hope he does that as opposed to having him go home.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Hill and Elder Parscal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/22/hill-and-elder-parscal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Hill and Elder Parscal" /><published>2000-11-22T20:45:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-22T20:45:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/22/hill-and-elder-parscal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/22/hill-and-elder-parscal.html"><![CDATA[<p>Tomorrow is Thanksgiving. We are going to have some time to write letters of thanks to friends and family. I think that I will write to Andrea and Jason.Well, today was really awesome. We had Brother Howard teach to us twice, and he is only our morning teacher. He told us about the “Hill of Howardess.”
![[Hill of howardess.jpg]]
As missionaries, we are higher up in understanding than other people on the hill. He said that we need to descend to their level and find out where they are. Through questioning, we can make it to their level and help pull them to our level. It was really cool because we did some role-playing and one of us as the missionary and Brother Howard was the investigator. He acted like one and forced us to ask a whole bunch of questions. We really learned a lot. He is a great teacher. He jokes around a lot, but he is wonderful.<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcj5ag2bMG4UDWd9wVuUtkb4ZhBsASC5c60fu-nhKZXL3T49qFKmPGrvb4NU6CmsmAnfZavosbhSguPHl9SUlULjNb565TiDv4euX5ZfvI_yEUBV90wVc1af1n5tJ8MCTUkG03Mj3wW0I7/s1600-h/Christmas+in+MTC+000.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcj5ag2bMG4UDWd9wVuUtkb4ZhBsASC5c60fu-nhKZXL3T49qFKmPGrvb4NU6CmsmAnfZavosbhSguPHl9SUlULjNb565TiDv4euX5ZfvI_yEUBV90wVc1af1n5tJ8MCTUkG03Mj3wW0I7/s400/Christmas+in+MTC+000.jpg" alt="" /></a>Elder Parscal asked me to give him a blessing of comfort this morning. The Lord blessed him that he would have a determination to serve the Lord. It was a great experience. I love the Lord so much and I am so thankful to be here. I love the Gospel.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="blessings" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tomorrow is Thanksgiving. We are going to have some time to write letters of thanks to friends and family. I think that I will write to Andrea and Jason.Well, today was really awesome. We had Brother Howard teach to us twice, and he is only our morning teacher. He told us about the “Hill of Howardess.” ![[Hill of howardess.jpg]] As missionaries, we are higher up in understanding than other people on the hill. He said that we need to descend to their level and find out where they are. Through questioning, we can make it to their level and help pull them to our level. It was really cool because we did some role-playing and one of us as the missionary and Brother Howard was the investigator. He acted like one and forced us to ask a whole bunch of questions. We really learned a lot. He is a great teacher. He jokes around a lot, but he is wonderful.Elder Parscal asked me to give him a blessing of comfort this morning. The Lord blessed him that he would have a determination to serve the Lord. It was a great experience. I love the Lord so much and I am so thankful to be here. I love the Gospel.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The First Mad Rush to Get it all Down</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/21/first-mad-rush-to-get-it-all-down.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The First Mad Rush to Get it all Down" /><published>2000-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/21/first-mad-rush-to-get-it-all-down</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/21/first-mad-rush-to-get-it-all-down.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was great. I am almost late for bed, but I would like to write in length about today tomorrow when I get up. I need to cover how Russian is coming, how classes were today, how I need to devote all my energy to the Lord. I need to talk about an apostle of the Lord speaking to us. I need to talk about the testimony meeting following, and about Elder Parscal.Okay, I must write fast and furious because we never have enough time. Russian is coming along well, I think. I really enjoy it. I am glad that I am doing so well. I know that the Lord is blessing me. I can say a medium-length prayer. My testimony is lacking, but I have 3 sentences in the first discussion, fifth principle down. I love the Lord.Elder Dallin H. Oaks of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles came and talked to all the missionaries at the MTC. As soon as he walked in the room, I could feel the Spirit of the Lord. I could tell that he was a man of God as soon as he started speaking. I could feel his power course through my body. What an amazing feeling! He spoke about many things, but the things that caught me the most are what I will write.He said that there is nothing more important in the field than each individual missionary and his testimony. “If one of us is lacking, we are all lacking.”He said to be successful, we must be obedient, and busy. He said that we must soon become full-time missionaries. There are different reasons for us to serve; starting with the least important reason, he said:*Personal advantage
*Good companionship
*Fear
*Duty
*Hope of eternal reward
*And most importantly, for the Love of ChristHe gave 
<a href="http://scriptures.lds.org/en/moro/7/48">Moroni 7:48</a> as the reference that we can use to pray for the love of Christ. [Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.]He also told the importance of baptizing families and not just teenagers. It is important to establish the church. And we must be clean. We must always teach by the spirit. We must obey ALL the rules. We must report our companions if they are not doing so. To make promises to not report is following the admonition of the 
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gadianton_robbers">Gadianton robbers</a>.We must work and gain trust of the members, so they will help us. We must set an example, we must love and act like proud missionaries of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.At our district meeting following, we all had wonderful comments about Elder Oaks’ talk. We all felt the spirit and had a testimony meeting following. Elder Parscal, who has really been having a horrible time, learned that he did have the spirit, and a desire to serve. He bore his testimony and we all could feel it powerfully. Elder Yoder told us why he came on a mission. He used to have a friend that he was really close to, but with whom he had never shared the gospel. He told us that he is afraid for when he crosses the veil and she says to him, “You had this wonderful plan of happiness and you never told me?” He doesn’t want to be held accountable for that. That would be horrible to lose a friend that you never shared the gospel with.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="why" /><category term="serve" /><category term="Apostle" /><category term="talks" /><category term="general" /><category term="authority" /><category term="testimony" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was great. I am almost late for bed, but I would like to write in length about today tomorrow when I get up. I need to cover how Russian is coming, how classes were today, how I need to devote all my energy to the Lord. I need to talk about an apostle of the Lord speaking to us. I need to talk about the testimony meeting following, and about Elder Parscal.Okay, I must write fast and furious because we never have enough time. Russian is coming along well, I think. I really enjoy it. I am glad that I am doing so well. I know that the Lord is blessing me. I can say a medium-length prayer. My testimony is lacking, but I have 3 sentences in the first discussion, fifth principle down. I love the Lord.Elder Dallin H. Oaks of the Quorum of the Twelve Apostles came and talked to all the missionaries at the MTC. As soon as he walked in the room, I could feel the Spirit of the Lord. I could tell that he was a man of God as soon as he started speaking. I could feel his power course through my body. What an amazing feeling! He spoke about many things, but the things that caught me the most are what I will write.He said that there is nothing more important in the field than each individual missionary and his testimony. “If one of us is lacking, we are all lacking.”He said to be successful, we must be obedient, and busy. He said that we must soon become full-time missionaries. There are different reasons for us to serve; starting with the least important reason, he said:*Personal advantage *Good companionship *Fear *Duty *Hope of eternal reward *And most importantly, for the Love of ChristHe gave Moroni 7:48 as the reference that we can use to pray for the love of Christ. [Wherefore, my beloved brethren, pray unto the Father with all the energy of heart, that ye may be filled with this love, which he hath bestowed upon all who are true followers of his Son, Jesus Christ; that ye may become the sons of God; that when he shall appear we shall be like him, for we shall see him as he is; that we may have this hope; that we may be purified even as he is pure. Amen.]He also told the importance of baptizing families and not just teenagers. It is important to establish the church. And we must be clean. We must always teach by the spirit. We must obey ALL the rules. We must report our companions if they are not doing so. To make promises to not report is following the admonition of the Gadianton robbers.We must work and gain trust of the members, so they will help us. We must set an example, we must love and act like proud missionaries of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.At our district meeting following, we all had wonderful comments about Elder Oaks’ talk. We all felt the spirit and had a testimony meeting following. Elder Parscal, who has really been having a horrible time, learned that he did have the spirit, and a desire to serve. He bore his testimony and we all could feel it powerfully. Elder Yoder told us why he came on a mission. He used to have a friend that he was really close to, but with whom he had never shared the gospel. He told us that he is afraid for when he crosses the veil and she says to him, “You had this wonderful plan of happiness and you never told me?” He doesn’t want to be held accountable for that. That would be horrible to lose a friend that you never shared the gospel with.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Elder Allred: DL</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/20/today-was-good-day-again.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elder Allred: DL" /><published>2000-11-20T20:47:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-20T20:47:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/20/today-was-good-day-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/20/today-was-good-day-again.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjBlV9qbp1c7FooyGuGJe3EmZcmFo8akRhH_GUNCNa1OXDAEMuJnNltaZmO3_I-Um3sKKuAy5oyx66s9ZHnaaEDBtRtsEgCI1FcMEf_zbLK92lvNi6TtigT5cVis9RwmgocnEW0Vps3buhy/s1600-h/Christmas+in+MTC+005.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjBlV9qbp1c7FooyGuGJe3EmZcmFo8akRhH_GUNCNa1OXDAEMuJnNltaZmO3_I-Um3sKKuAy5oyx66s9ZHnaaEDBtRtsEgCI1FcMEf_zbLK92lvNi6TtigT5cVis9RwmgocnEW0Vps3buhy/s400/Christmas+in+MTC+005.jpg" alt="" /></a>Today was a good day, again. I really love it here. Yesterday, Elder Allred from Virginia was called, or appointed to be our District Leader. He is a ver good person. I am glad that he is our D.L. I knew before he was called that he was going to be our D.L. I could just tell. I really like him. I think he is going to be very good. I see him as a friend that I may be able to keep for life. I would really like that. I told him I was positive it was going to be him. He said that he thought it would be me. I thought it was really cool that he said that. I really respect him.</p>

<p>I got a letter from my father today. It was very cool. He said he was going to try and take Russian at a community college. He is a good man. I love him. I pray in Russian now; it is really cool.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="letter from home" /><category term="callings" /><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was a good day, again. I really love it here. Yesterday, Elder Allred from Virginia was called, or appointed to be our District Leader. He is a ver good person. I am glad that he is our D.L. I knew before he was called that he was going to be our D.L. I could just tell. I really like him. I think he is going to be very good. I see him as a friend that I may be able to keep for life. I would really like that. I told him I was positive it was going to be him. He said that he thought it would be me. I thought it was really cool that he said that. I really respect him.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Sunday</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/19/first-sunday.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Sunday" /><published>2000-11-19T20:45:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-19T20:45:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/19/first-sunday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/19/first-sunday.html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was once again, awesome. Church was really good. Our Branch President, President Mendenhall, is really cool. He has a lot of love and gusto for the church. We had a fireside tonight for the whole MTC. The speakers were the President of the MTC and his wife. We sang six songs and they told missionary stories. It was so great. I love singing praises to our God and King. He is great.</p>

<p>Then we went to another fireside about temples. That was awesome. We were counseled by President Nixon to wear our garments properly. That was the gist of it. We sang “High on the Mountaintop.” That is a great song. I prayed with my district tonight in Russian again. It was really cool. I love it here.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="Church" /><category term="Hymns" /><category term="learning" /><category term="language" /><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today was once again, awesome. Church was really good. Our Branch President, President Mendenhall, is really cool. He has a lot of love and gusto for the church. We had a fireside tonight for the whole MTC. The speakers were the President of the MTC and his wife. We sang six songs and they told missionary stories. It was so great. I love singing praises to our God and King. He is great.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">P-Days are the Pits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/18/p-days-are-pits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="P-Days are the Pits" /><published>2000-11-18T22:55:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-18T22:55:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/18/p-days-are-pits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/18/p-days-are-pits.html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, today was a good day. I feel that I am getting a better grasp each day. It was preparation day today, which means that we have four hours to clean and be ready for the next week. It was good, because while was waiting for my laundry to be completed, I wrote letters: one to George and Amy, one to Kathy, one to Becky Simmons, one to Ty and Tish Curry. It was good, but made me a little homesick. We have our first Sunday tomorrow. I am pretty excited. I really love church. I am so thankful to God for blessing me as he has. I said a prayer tonight in Russian; it was my first time and it was cool. I love Russian.</p>

<p>[As you will undoubtedly notice, the ends of some of my entries will be very strange. My goal was to write one page every day, and some days, that was incredibly difficult. I may just start deleting that stuff.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well, today was a good day. I feel that I am getting a better grasp each day. It was preparation day today, which means that we have four hours to clean and be ready for the next week. It was good, because while was waiting for my laundry to be completed, I wrote letters: one to George and Amy, one to Kathy, one to Becky Simmons, one to Ty and Tish Curry. It was good, but made me a little homesick. We have our first Sunday tomorrow. I am pretty excited. I really love church. I am so thankful to God for blessing me as he has. I said a prayer tonight in Russian; it was my first time and it was cool. I love Russian.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trying to Help</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/17/what-day-it-started-out-pretty-bad.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trying to Help" /><published>2000-11-17T22:43:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-17T22:43:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/17/what-day-it-started-out-pretty-bad</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/17/what-day-it-started-out-pretty-bad.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAUQzIN5uDFY8GSwHHwn5WwnWhyphenhyphenbUtSL8Cr_jKuyV2rgFkMGus5C8jID5elzSNaQJ1UAhNwNN7UIYF3lTu7vawSGt6NJtg7189lwhpGVTyQbf1UKuCl4MDMHimF2NCzku5W4iXx4rvGTtL/s1600-h/MTC+Day+3+000.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgAUQzIN5uDFY8GSwHHwn5WwnWhyphenhyphenbUtSL8Cr_jKuyV2rgFkMGus5C8jID5elzSNaQJ1UAhNwNN7UIYF3lTu7vawSGt6NJtg7189lwhpGVTyQbf1UKuCl4MDMHimF2NCzku5W4iXx4rvGTtL/s400/MTC+Day+3+000.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiYtoUZzBU2Ft3O8-X1wAmtGEGSV3Gl_phdg-8CSoB68ZkFOzGq5fQp7rcl2tNF7Yz3UlZvmjsuV7yjALNR_PEylBWHMmaHbI2MjidaImpmZGdX1qEX1AzLSxifXGL3HNMkD1tMOqxhp27H/s1600-h/MTC+Day+3+001.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiYtoUZzBU2Ft3O8-X1wAmtGEGSV3Gl_phdg-8CSoB68ZkFOzGq5fQp7rcl2tNF7Yz3UlZvmjsuV7yjALNR_PEylBWHMmaHbI2MjidaImpmZGdX1qEX1AzLSxifXGL3HNMkD1tMOqxhp27H/s400/MTC+Day+3+001.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg0eJlLfxyxXtI3qDomnmhCby03WS_xbd3D5PdN8R_2tx8WtaD3KTlYSLS7mAtuliJRGbS9AvsF3Fz7eOuN6ATpmcYivUwqzr6HLEsY3yt18W-tSnM9-Kbx8w50wT7tskddk6TkEJ1KpqtD/s1600-h/MTC+Day+3+002.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg0eJlLfxyxXtI3qDomnmhCby03WS_xbd3D5PdN8R_2tx8WtaD3KTlYSLS7mAtuliJRGbS9AvsF3Fz7eOuN6ATpmcYivUwqzr6HLEsY3yt18W-tSnM9-Kbx8w50wT7tskddk6TkEJ1KpqtD/s400/MTC+Day+3+002.jpg" alt="" /></a>What a day! It started out pretty bad. I was very frustrated with my inability to learn Russian [understandably so, after 16 hours of trying to figure it out, I should have it mastered]. I was complaining and bothering the spirit for my roommates. Then, later, I was still frustrated, but at least I was not complaining. I just had a sour look on my face. Then one of my companions told us that he didn’t feel like he should be here. We told him it was Satan being a jerk and being evil. I bore my testimony and we prayed. We asked Heavenly Father for his Spirit to be with us. We went to class and towards the end, we had to teach the first discussion, and as I was teaching, I could feel the spirit. Then, when Elder Parscal started to teach, I could really feel the Spirit. He taught with such power. It was awesome. When we got back, we told him that we felt the Spirit when he was teaching. It was great. He still had doubts, but by the Spirit of our wonderful Heavenly Father, we were able to help Elder Parscal feel the Spirit and know that Heavenly Father loves him. God is wonderful. I love Him so much. When I bore my testimony before, it was through Heavenly Father’s grace and power. I pray that I may always recognize His hand in all things. I love Him so much. I know that His hand is always there and if I keep His commandments, I will live with Him again.</p>

<p>I received my first letter today. It was from Amy, my sister. She just wrote to tell me that she loves me and is very proud of me. I love her very much and I am so happy that she is my sister. I love this church and I love this gospel. It is late, and I must retire. (We learned how to write in Russian tonight and it was cool).
[Amy would become the best letter write in the family. It was always so cool to get a letter from her. I got a lot and I have them all (or at least most of them) in a 3-inch three-ring binder. Thanks, Hunzy!]</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What a day! It started out pretty bad. I was very frustrated with my inability to learn Russian [understandably so, after 16 hours of trying to figure it out, I should have it mastered]. I was complaining and bothering the spirit for my roommates. Then, later, I was still frustrated, but at least I was not complaining. I just had a sour look on my face. Then one of my companions told us that he didn’t feel like he should be here. We told him it was Satan being a jerk and being evil. I bore my testimony and we prayed. We asked Heavenly Father for his Spirit to be with us. We went to class and towards the end, we had to teach the first discussion, and as I was teaching, I could feel the spirit. Then, when Elder Parscal started to teach, I could really feel the Spirit. He taught with such power. It was awesome. When we got back, we told him that we felt the Spirit when he was teaching. It was great. He still had doubts, but by the Spirit of our wonderful Heavenly Father, we were able to help Elder Parscal feel the Spirit and know that Heavenly Father loves him. God is wonderful. I love Him so much. When I bore my testimony before, it was through Heavenly Father’s grace and power. I pray that I may always recognize His hand in all things. I love Him so much. I know that His hand is always there and if I keep His commandments, I will live with Him again.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stating the Obvious: Russian is Hard on Your First Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/16/stating-obvious-russian-is-hard-on-your.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stating the Obvious: Russian is Hard on Your First Day" /><published>2000-11-16T22:35:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-16T22:35:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/16/stating-obvious-russian-is-hard-on-your</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/16/stating-obvious-russian-is-hard-on-your.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgOxuQh9ikD5VkRLz989MsKlAgbZ3HsPtJA0G8pEPynMxmJI8xm82sdbOFBmfBnLLSJOlQKq6CdIDxr6d2KTg_JoAyddxE5xgKzGEJl0PVNERMg86MDJBPgKSNBoTJZtxghN7Ns2XXxMlaY/s1600-h/MTC+Day+2+000.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgOxuQh9ikD5VkRLz989MsKlAgbZ3HsPtJA0G8pEPynMxmJI8xm82sdbOFBmfBnLLSJOlQKq6CdIDxr6d2KTg_JoAyddxE5xgKzGEJl0PVNERMg86MDJBPgKSNBoTJZtxghN7Ns2XXxMlaY/s400/MTC+Day+2+000.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjxXUvDZ6HY06xLowwWMEycy5Tz1z3RtNCV3uX6dCK8FxTjLnD4iOp6ZaVj3bnGYjAtVGuzle1ROSYABawWSmylQJUKTGiCrQUxMZlCi5VBhTSJ9_CXpcFWaANRKw_USwsjHAJ7-T1pkuvi/s1600-h/MTC+Day+2+001.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjxXUvDZ6HY06xLowwWMEycy5Tz1z3RtNCV3uX6dCK8FxTjLnD4iOp6ZaVj3bnGYjAtVGuzle1ROSYABawWSmylQJUKTGiCrQUxMZlCi5VBhTSJ9_CXpcFWaANRKw_USwsjHAJ7-T1pkuvi/s400/MTC+Day+2+001.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiu4lNSt4MhrIA6MhJKyNTJYao6sXky_6QC4pauDRLTyjQjAoMwASJ8W1I4H9cVnQXehmSUhFN2DJH0rOl45tYWZm-FBgMZSRB8omZc9hsSKZtWWjr7K-BzliIrziKX1JlTcRy1mmOm3igZ/s1600-h/MTC+Day+2+002.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiu4lNSt4MhrIA6MhJKyNTJYao6sXky_6QC4pauDRLTyjQjAoMwASJ8W1I4H9cVnQXehmSUhFN2DJH0rOl45tYWZm-FBgMZSRB8omZc9hsSKZtWWjr7K-BzliIrziKX1JlTcRy1mmOm3igZ/s400/MTC+Day+2+002.jpg" alt="" /></a>Here it is, my second day. It is a happy day because we dove into the language. It is also a sad day because Elder Williams, my companion, was called home. he had issues that he needed to deal with. he can’t come back for four months. That is really sad. I really loved him [what?]. He had a great testimony. I am sad to see him go, but I pray that he will make it back.</p>

<p>Russian is very hard! I am still having a bit of difficulty with the alphabet [duh! It is only your first day ever seeing it!]. I know that if I am humble and prayerful and hardworking, the Lord will bless me and loose my tongue.</p>

<p>I do not have a companion yet, and I fell very alone. I miss Elder Williams. The two other elders in my room are Elder Parscal (the R is silent) and Elder Reich. They are cool. I love them, too. I miss my family :(, but I am not homesick. I miss Kathy greatly :(. If I remember, I will write my impressions of the MTC tomorrow.</p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="sent home" /><category term="learning" /><category term="language" /><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here it is, my second day. It is a happy day because we dove into the language. It is also a sad day because Elder Williams, my companion, was called home. he had issues that he needed to deal with. he can’t come back for four months. That is really sad. I really loved him [what?]. He had a great testimony. I am sad to see him go, but I pray that he will make it back.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reporting for Duty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/15/reporting-for-duty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reporting for Duty" /><published>2000-11-15T22:16:00-08:00</published><updated>2000-11-15T22:16:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2000/11/15/reporting-for-duty</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2000/11/15/reporting-for-duty.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhUtGoOJ5EOfKdzLkEM1fUBbgzsf582cia9jXKSLh4gVSZdpNVU4Gr-3yjDL3Dw0aGrHK3Wc3N4BGapTRte5SycFTYSrgm8C8cKgJZEOkMJO8pLG5PngRxhd8Xn0_xWeSbirScCTcKPes1f/s1600-h/image.request.php.jpeg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhUtGoOJ5EOfKdzLkEM1fUBbgzsf582cia9jXKSLh4gVSZdpNVU4Gr-3yjDL3Dw0aGrHK3Wc3N4BGapTRte5SycFTYSrgm8C8cKgJZEOkMJO8pLG5PngRxhd8Xn0_xWeSbirScCTcKPes1f/s400/image.request.php.jpeg" alt="" /></a>
<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgiLdtzLGtvzxoOU5ik1QjNf11sILZaBRTEa_8p7mYoOWlq7oMO5zMoaDc9WFTqfGFMjni5KxV0g7xIaebZpRin5mWJJ__4702el9H5TG-kwfrqZu5HbKF8y7LvFXa3F3ScPBPGsc_oUChA/s1600-h/001+MTC+Day+1+.jpeg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgiLdtzLGtvzxoOU5ik1QjNf11sILZaBRTEa_8p7mYoOWlq7oMO5zMoaDc9WFTqfGFMjni5KxV0g7xIaebZpRin5mWJJ__4702el9H5TG-kwfrqZu5HbKF8y7LvFXa3F3ScPBPGsc_oUChA/s400/001+MTC+Day+1+.jpeg" alt="" /></a>
<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiIIEm9yWrXU9mwjIyQcvHO_u5TWmqvK4deJnsU4Fy_GlvHwMglanXLMx-mMGTyzj4iyTgqqu_2FyeC6qCKa5zu4AUthrijKpV4yLikR24DS_tLjA8EYPXHuOeNt_BBxIXRpOsDboL4MrNc/s1600-h/002+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiIIEm9yWrXU9mwjIyQcvHO_u5TWmqvK4deJnsU4Fy_GlvHwMglanXLMx-mMGTyzj4iyTgqqu_2FyeC6qCKa5zu4AUthrijKpV4yLikR24DS_tLjA8EYPXHuOeNt_BBxIXRpOsDboL4MrNc/s400/002+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I don’t have much time to write so I will go fast. I reported today. My companion is Elder Travis Williams. He is from American Fork, UT.</p>

<p>I have two things that I want to make sure I get out tonight. On the way here, I realized that the adversary does not want me here. When we left my grandmother’s house, it was snowing heavily, and that was a little scary [boy, was I in a for a surprise when I got to Russia!]. Then, as we were driving, we asked my dad [via walkie-talkies] if he wanted to lead the way, and he said no, he would feel more comfortable if my mom and I led the way. We were driving and we somehow got a flat tire we had to stop to change in the snow. Then we got to Provo, stopped at Shopko, and Amy’s car battery died. It was sad.</p>

<p>The other thing was that in my patriarchal blessing it says that I would be blessed if I went on a mission. One blessing is that my fear would be in control. All day, I have not been nervous. I have tried to be humble and prayerful, and my prayers have been answered. A wonderful feeling of calm and comfort was with me while my family was balling their eyes out. I love the Lord so much and without Him, I would be nothing.
[I need to clarify a few things here. When I was a kid, I got scared anytime I was away from home. It is so bizarre to me now, but that is how it was. Before camping trips I would be a wreck, sick to my stomach and unable to do anything but worry. The first day of school was always absolutely horrible. Even my first year of college, I didn’t think that I could make it through those first couple days. Any time there was a big change, I became so nervous that I was incapable of doing anything. I have so many vivid memories of being sick to my stomach with worry. That is why this was so amazing. The day I was making the biggest change in my life and doing something so drastic was completely free of worry, fear, and nervousness. That blessing that I received could not be more true. It is possible that I had all those bad experiences to fulfill this promise. From that day on, I have never felt nervous about a big change in my life. I am sure I mention that later, but I want to be sure and record it now.]<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcfwcAmRZsw7ymsa-yPFrO3ls6SWyiOzNFkDzurudERn12kJxvA0DUmZMf-h7T8T4hLZUooNv1i96gGbPsma6Dw8Un3Eg7xLen0lxEcxFLbntpCXIoyQqRejntA9ezSmhYH7h5VUqLu2NX/s1600-h/003+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhcfwcAmRZsw7ymsa-yPFrO3ls6SWyiOzNFkDzurudERn12kJxvA0DUmZMf-h7T8T4hLZUooNv1i96gGbPsma6Dw8Un3Eg7xLen0lxEcxFLbntpCXIoyQqRejntA9ezSmhYH7h5VUqLu2NX/s400/003+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a>
<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh4j0V-PePOPvOQuOuH3cCQGdG6vEHUihusGVpKvwUSiAblnmw_x1amqcaTw3FYanbgN5mir4S-c6r1cuiuasdxH2pQa_F7h4rTmAEmb0LuoNaMIFpCeidnfWWk_O34acyzwoc1YtqpmMDC/s1600-h/004+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh4j0V-PePOPvOQuOuH3cCQGdG6vEHUihusGVpKvwUSiAblnmw_x1amqcaTw3FYanbgN5mir4S-c6r1cuiuasdxH2pQa_F7h4rTmAEmb0LuoNaMIFpCeidnfWWk_O34acyzwoc1YtqpmMDC/s400/004+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a>
<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjt4umr9n3kmUN4X2YjIxHCyjLmnCmf49UD1MgxynZNCQspA00csVA85y9Z9BxM7tmiZW5ri-dkT_DABQAGX1oLxCugpc2UWMqqgoQ0yC2w7L8VHgtu4RyFrIbt9LrGEwwaBF3Rol6PLXHC/s1600-h/010+MTC+Day+1.jpeg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjt4umr9n3kmUN4X2YjIxHCyjLmnCmf49UD1MgxynZNCQspA00csVA85y9Z9BxM7tmiZW5ri-dkT_DABQAGX1oLxCugpc2UWMqqgoQ0yC2w7L8VHgtu4RyFrIbt9LrGEwwaBF3Rol6PLXHC/s400/010+MTC+Day+1.jpeg" alt="" /></a>
<a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgwqtLlIn3PYTTKlhuGgAKQwjnJCmt2_Z0Wyof0YTpIzo7q1mM5y04br-tRwMkzDDhXzTWBLkGeZtv_CefAQ5wVaQbhC5_gkPewu7z8ycVkSPbakIRAY4ssGiusaNjMqJBi4PTo40mFd6vk/s1600-h/009+MTC+Day+1.jpeg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgwqtLlIn3PYTTKlhuGgAKQwjnJCmt2_Z0Wyof0YTpIzo7q1mM5y04br-tRwMkzDDhXzTWBLkGeZtv_CefAQ5wVaQbhC5_gkPewu7z8ycVkSPbakIRAY4ssGiusaNjMqJBi4PTo40mFd6vk/s400/009+MTC+Day+1.jpeg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgDm76iCytoQpRBkyOvcUNZ9UGUaQIdZtmRljUVwCg8Hn8Zctmn_oA8vu__lljWXqyZsCsMDjEkI6c1ANIRdK37JWQ1ID2WYqztNeHnOStSFKEBmbFoMvcaopbzW2g_FBEifFC9YgJJiHNC/s1600-h/006+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgDm76iCytoQpRBkyOvcUNZ9UGUaQIdZtmRljUVwCg8Hn8Zctmn_oA8vu__lljWXqyZsCsMDjEkI6c1ANIRdK37JWQ1ID2WYqztNeHnOStSFKEBmbFoMvcaopbzW2g_FBEifFC9YgJJiHNC/s400/006+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgNDENkP4wDWcNtw2g_9-PPq_xlRzrbPD_pbAOYFCCBE-d600d4Xat60YfDFSwS7gXwwRSsXE2XA8R8VrwdenV3mqQNo5LzmsN_cVU48zY7tYlOmbs-qtM7m6zGWf6VnFwK1YX7OUrbYE7X/s1600-h/007+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgNDENkP4wDWcNtw2g_9-PPq_xlRzrbPD_pbAOYFCCBE-d600d4Xat60YfDFSwS7gXwwRSsXE2XA8R8VrwdenV3mqQNo5LzmsN_cVU48zY7tYlOmbs-qtM7m6zGWf6VnFwK1YX7OUrbYE7X/s400/007+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjRwmgCekBkDwYOSy3nwcSTa8iCpQYizKyOwt00ZyM64FC-d3pn3t3FA9E4yU9p5w4jDvCcf-L0Xt5OGmHpaeZf4-2KH0oEpzrXsTzj-Fo1V46lWfTiYGSU_QjEjRTN0BbEvLlvyczNFLCb/s1600-h/008+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjRwmgCekBkDwYOSy3nwcSTa8iCpQYizKyOwt00ZyM64FC-d3pn3t3FA9E4yU9p5w4jDvCcf-L0Xt5OGmHpaeZf4-2KH0oEpzrXsTzj-Fo1V46lWfTiYGSU_QjEjRTN0BbEvLlvyczNFLCb/s400/008+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi89dKXAGpG_zIjdqneRFu1gf8gWupu-4RyI4HEPoxVzipp-aXwXYHbiusVpqYbo4cwLQ1ZMgy8UNY8UA2hsIKD6PY3YV72uNRJXcmQE3bOzTnRM0APP6Bhq53TdYde6tJKkh00t_cwJMz4/s1600-h/005+MTC+Day+1+.jpg"><img src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEi89dKXAGpG_zIjdqneRFu1gf8gWupu-4RyI4HEPoxVzipp-aXwXYHbiusVpqYbo4cwLQ1ZMgy8UNY8UA2hsIKD6PY3YV72uNRJXcmQE3bOzTnRM0APP6Bhq53TdYde6tJKkh00t_cwJMz4/s400/005+MTC+Day+1+.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name>jethrojones</name></author><category term="MTC" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>